Guide to the George Sherwood Eddy Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, Series II
  - Writings: Articles and Speeches
    - "Stepanic's Hat is Blood Red", "Why a Red Hat for Stepanic?", 1953 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - "Tito and Rome", 1953 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - "With Tito in Yugoslavia", c. 1953 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - "Youth Will Decide", 1955 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - "Marshall Tito and Peace", 1956 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - "A New Nation", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - "An Interview With China's First President.. .", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - "A Visit to Vienna", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - "Birth Control in Asia", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - "Eternal China", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - "Methodist Mission in the Far East", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - "The Hope of China", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - "The Philippines and the Malay Archipelago" (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - "The Philippine Question", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - "Milestones in Advancing Experience", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - "What I Believe", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - "The Fateful Decision", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - "The Searchlight on Bulgaria", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - "The Simon Report", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - "Is America Being Educated?", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - "The Social Message.. .", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - "The Social Principles of Jesus", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - "How God Became Real to Me", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - "The Work of Arthur Ford", "The Crisis in India", n.d., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - "The Evolution of the Soul After Death", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - "Hong Kong and China" (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - "How Can We Build a New China.. .", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - "Israel Forever", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - "A New Easter Message", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - "Shall We Use Chiang's Troops.. .", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - "Understanding Russia" (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - "What Are the Great Essentials?", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Book review, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Oversize: Phonograph recordings of GSE speeches: (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - "Lost Secret of Life", "Our Atomic World", n.d., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Broadcast on Radio Hong Kong, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Writings: Pamphlets
    - "The Supreme Decision.. .", 1893,1895 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - "Steps in the Christian Life", 1907 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - "Doubt.. .", 1907,1913,1920 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - "Studies in the Book of Acts", 1909 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - "Studies in the Epistles and Revelation of John", 1910 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - "Victory", 1913 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - "Outward Practice", 1914 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - "What is Christianity?", 1914 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - "The Practical Programme of Christianity", 1914 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - "Suggestions to Workers" (with W. E. Taylor), 1914 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - "The Meaning of Suffering", 1916 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - "Life.. .", 1916 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - "The Maker of Men", 1917 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - "Constructive Suggestions for Character Building" (with John R. Mott), 1917 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - "Famine Stricken India", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - "The Faith of Honest Doubt", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - "Temptation and How to Meet It", 1920 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - "Personal Evangelism.. .", 1920 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - "The Greatest Work in the World", 1921 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - "America: Its Problems and Perils", 1922 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "Russia.. .', 1923 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "The Abolition of War", 1924 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "The Faith of Honest Doubt", 1924 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "Jesus Christ- What is His Significance?", 1924 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "The Modernist Fundamentalist Controversy", 1924 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "Science and Religion", 1924 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - "Danger Zones of the Social Order" (with K. Page), 1926 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - "Religion and Social Justice", 1927 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - "Sex and Youth", 1928 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - "Am I Getting an Education?", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - "The Challenge of Russia", 1931 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - "The Challenge of the East", 1932 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - "Dynamic Religion" (Eddy et al), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - "What Shall We Do About War?" (with K. Page), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - "The Meaning of Marx" (introduction only), 1934 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - "Doom and Dawn" (with Reinhold Niebuhr), 1936 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - "Why America Fights", 1942 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - "A Door of Opportunity on an American Adventure in Cooperation with Sharecroppers", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - "The Supreme Decision.. .", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - "Entering Marriage", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - "Something Better than a Fortune", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - "The Man Who is Right", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - "How God Became Real to Me", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - "The Industrial Problem" (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - "How China's Leaders Received the Gospel", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - "The Opportunity of the Hour", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Writings: Related to Major Works
    - A Pilgrimage of Ideas Index, by H. Robinson Shipherd, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - The Gold Seeker: the Life and Times of Raymond Robins (unpublished), draft, c.1947 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - The Gold Seeker, notes and correspondence, c.1947 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - You Will Survive After Death, draft, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - You Will Survive After Death, notes and memoranda, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - You Will Survive After Death, correspondence, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - You Will Survive After Death, correspondence, royalty statements, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - You Will Survive After Death, reviews, publicity, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - World History in the Making (unpublished), drafts, c.1951 (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - World History in the Making, drafts, c.1951 (Box 8, Folder 156)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, drafts: chapters 1-2, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 157)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, drafts: chapters 3-4, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 158)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, drafts: chapters 5-6, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 159)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, drafts: chapters 7-8, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, drafts: chapters 9-14, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, notes, drafts, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 162)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, notes, drafts, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 163)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, reviews, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 164)
    - How to Live (unpublished), preliminary drafts, c.1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - How to Live, preliminary drafts, c.1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - How to Live, final draft, c.1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - How to Live, correspondence, c.1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 168)
    - Why I Believe (unpublished), chapters 1-4, c.1956 (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - Why I Believe, chapters 5-8, c.1956 (Box 10, Folder 170)
    - Why I Believe, drafts, c.1956 (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - The Undying World Revolution (unpublished), drafts: chapters 1-2 (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - The Undying World Revolution, drafts: chapters 3-5 (Box 10, Folder 173)
    - The Undying World Revolution, drafts: chapters 6-7 (Box 10, Folder 174)
  - Writings: Notes and Fragments
    - Re. Arthur Ford and spiritualism, 1938-1955 (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Re. Asia, c.1955, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Re. China, 1935, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Re. Great Britain, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Re. Israel, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 179)
    - Re. Japan, Korea, 1955, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - Notebooks, c.1926, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - Notes for miscellaneous speeches, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 182)
    - Re. Russia, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 183)
    - Re. United States, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 184)
    - Re. various European countries, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 11, Folder 186)
  - Writings: Published Works
    - The Abolition of War, 1924 (Box 12)
    - Am I Getting an Education?, 1929 (Box 12)
    - A Century with Youth, 1944 (Box 12)
    - The Challenge of Europe, 1933 (Box 12)
    - Christ and Revolution, 1939 (Box 12)
    - Creative Pioneers, 1937 (Box 13)
    - "Doom and Dawn", 1936 (Box 13)
    - "A Door of Opportunity", n.d. (Box 13)
    - Eighty Adventurous Years, 1955 (Box 13)
    - "Entering Marriage", n.d. (Box 13)
    - Europe Today, 1937 (Box 13)
    - Everybody's World, 1920 (Box 13)
    - Facing the Crisis, 1922 (Box 13)
    - God in History, 1947 (Box 13)
    - "How God Became Real to Me", n.d. (Box 13)
    - "I Have Seen God Do It", 1940 (Box 14)
    - "I Have Seen God Work in China", 1944 (Box 14)
    - India Awakening.., 1911 (Box 14)
    - "Introduction to the Study of the New Testament", (in "Selections from Records of the Life of Jesus"), 1924 (Box 14)
    - The Kingdom of God and The American Dream, 1941 (Box 14)
    - "Life and What to Live For", 1916 (Box 14)
    - "The Maker of Men", 1917 (Box 14)
    - Maker of Men, 1941 (Box 14)
    - Makers of Freedom, 1926 (Box 14)
    - Man Discovers God, 1942 (Box 15)
    - "The Man Who Is Right", n.d. (Box 15)
    - New Challenges to Faith, 1926 (Box 15)
    - The New Era in Asia, 1913 (Box 15)
    - The New World of Labor, 1923 (Box 15)
    - Pathfinders of the World Missionary Crusade, 1945 (Box 15)
    - A Pilgrimage of Ideas, 1934 (Box 15)
    - A Portrait of Jesus, 1943 (Box 15)
    - "The Practical Programme of Christianity", 1914 (Box 16)
    - Religion and Social Justice, 1927 (Box 16)
    - Revolutionary Christianity, 1939 (Box 16)
    - The Right to Fight, 1918 (Box 16)
    - Schuldner der Welt (Eighty Adventurous Years, Ger.), 1955 (Box 16)
    - "Sex Youth", 1928 (Box 16)
    - Studies in the Book of Acts, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Studies in the Pauline Epistles, 1906 (Box 16)
    - The Students of Asia, 1916 (Box 16)
    - Suffering and the War, 1916 (Box 16)
    - "Suggestions to Workers", 1914 (Box 16)
    - "The Supreme Decision of the Christian Student", 1920 (Box 16)
    - Tachtig Avontuurlijke Jaren, 1959 (Box 16)
    - "Why America Fights", 1942 (Box 17)
    - With Our Soldiers in France, 1917 (Box 17)
    - You Will Survive After Death; You Will Survive Death (Great Britain), 1950, 1954 (Box 17)
      One copy of You Will Survive After Death has photographs pasted into the back that illustrate occult phenomena.
- Collected Material, 1917; Series III
  The material in this series is arranged in a general alphabetical sequence according to topic and chronologically within topics. The miscellaneous published works by others are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Arden Eddy's copy of Daily Readings in the Gospel of Mark by Wm. D. Murray, presented by GSE, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - re. China, 1955, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - rb. Colton, Ethan T., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - re. Cooperative farms and the South, 1938, 1947, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - re. Czechoslovakia, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - re. Great Britain (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - re. India, incl. re. Gandhi, 1941, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - re. India, incl. re. Ahmednagar College, 1949-1958 (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - re. Israel (Box 18, Folder 195)
  - re. Japan, 1948-1954, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 196)
  - re. Korea, 1950-1955 (Box 18, Folder 197)
  - Published works by others: Eddy Page Publications: (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - Industry Series: No. 14, "Property", K. Page (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - Industry Series: No. 15, "Capitalism and its Rivals", K. Page (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - World Problems Series: No. 18, "Mahatma Gandhi and His Significance", K. Page, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - Problems Series: No. 21, "Creative Society", John Macmurray, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - Published works by others: miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Butterfield, Oliver M., "Marriage", 1929 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Curry, Bruce, et al, "Students and the Religion of To-day", 1926 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Eddy, David Brewer, What Next in Turkey?, 1913 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - National Council on Student Christian Work, "It is the Christian Faith", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Oldham, J. H., "Christianity and the Race Problem", 1925 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Page, Kirby, "Collective Bargaining", 1921 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - ____, "Industrial Facts", 1921 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - ____, "Jesus or Christianity", 1929 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Page, Kirby, "The Meek Shall Inherit the Earth", 1948 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - ____, "What Does God Want Us to do about Russia?", 1948 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Popley, H. A., et al, "Three Y.M.C.A. Pioneers", 1958 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Rowntree, B. Seebohm, "Industrial Unrest: A Way Out", 1922 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Sharman, H. B., Records of the Life of Jesus, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Simkhovitch, Vladimir G., "Toward the Understanding of Jesus", 1923 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Wright, Helena, "The Sex Factor in Marriage", 1931 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - re. Soviet Union, 1956, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - re. Spiritualism, Arthur Ford, 1941, 1971, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - Y. T. Wu's condemnation of GSE, Y.M.C.A., etc., c.1949 (Box 19, Folder 202)
  - re. Yugoslavia, 1947-1954 (Box 19, Folder 203)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series IV
  a. Biographical Documentation:The material is arranged chronologically with folder headings giving some indication of format or topic.
  Material Related to Seminars and Lectures: The material is arranged chronologically.
  Financial Records:The material is arranged chronologically.
  Genealogical Material: The items included are listed individually.
  Photographs: The photographs are arranged in topical groupings.
  - Biographical Documentation
    - Scrapbook of clippings, corres. and documents re. Eddy and Norton families, 1851-1894 (Box 20, Folder 204)
    - Miscellaneous, 1911-1927 (Box 20, Folder 205)
    - Incl. re. GSE retirement from YMCA, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 206)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1938 (Box 20, Folder 207)
    - Incl. letter to D. B. Eddy and Reinhold Niebuhr and "The Eddy Family History" by GSE, 1942-1944 (Box 20, Folder 208)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1954 (Box 20, Folder 209)
    - Miscellaneous, 1955-1959 (Box 20, Folder 210)
    - Re. 90th birthday of GSE, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 211)
    - Obituaries and tributes following death of GSE, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 212)
    - Re. Symposium in honor of GSE, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 213)
    - Tributes, 1971, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 214)
    - Re. GSE papers at YDSL, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 215)
    - Miscellaneous and fragments (Box 20, Folder 216)
    - Diplomas: Phillips Academy 1888; Yale 1891;Princeton, 1896; College of Wooster Princeton, 1896;1902, 1917 (Box OV1)
  - Material Related to Seminars and Lectures
    - Seminars and Lectures, 1914-1949 (Box 21, Folder 217-219)
    - Additional materials related to the 1938 Seminar: VCR tape and DVD of 8mm film taken by Joseph S. Ewing, with audio voice-over by John M. and Sharon D. Ewing from the original journals of Ewing, roster of participants in the Seminar, photocopy of a photograph of the participants, and "In Their Own Words" DVD of manuscript of journals and lecture notes of Joseph Ewing. (Box 24, Folder 243-245)
    - Seminars and Lectures, 1950-1958 (Box 21, Folder 220-226)
    - Seminars and Lectures (Box 21, Folder 227)
  - Financial Records
    - Financial records, 1928-1946 (Box 22, Folder 228)
    - Financial records, 1959-1975, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 229)
  - Genealogical Material
    - The Eddy Family in America; The Eddy Family Heritage Book, 1930, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 230)
    - "The Eddy Family in America, 1630-1930" (Box 22, Folder 230)
    - "A Short History of St. Dunstan's Church", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 230)
    - The Eddy Family Association Bulletin, XXVI, No. 1, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 230)
  - Photographs
    - Portraits of GSE, c.1872-1954, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 231)
    - Portraits of family members (see also: oversize), c.1913-1940s, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 232)
    - Group photos including GSE (incl. commemoration of 90th birthday), c.1917-1961, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 233)
    - Photos from Eddy's seminar trips, 1921-1930, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 234)
    - Early photos from China, Eddy meetings in Foochow and Hong Kong (see also: oversize), 1913 (Box 23, Folder 235)
    - Early photos from China - taken from souvenir album sent to Chinese officials following lecture tour by Eddy and C. H. Robertson (including map of tour and captions), 1914-1915 (Box 23, Folder 236)
    - Miscellaneous photos from China, c.1915-1936, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 237)
    - Photos of buildings and scenes in India (Box 23, Folder 238)
    - Photos of individuals in India - incl. early group photo of Indian Christian leaders and photos of Gandhi, 1905, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 239)
    - Album including photos of Dr. Eddy Hall, Kirubakarar Orphanage, India, 1949-1956, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 240)
    - Photos of Korean Christian leaders and prisoners (Box 23, Folder 241)
    - Photo of Hitler on day of world broadcast from Berlin, 1934 Jul 13 (Box 23, Folder 242)